Ravi Panchal

Scrum Master/Project Manager

Certified Scrum Master/Project Manager with around over 12 years of experience. Love to challenge myself and solve problems. Technology enthusiast and eager to learn about every new technology out there. What makes me different is that I am Project Manager / Scrum Master with serious Technical skills. Acting as Chief Technical Officer for Non-Profit Organization that helps sponsor student education in INDIA for under privileged children.













www.ravi-panchal.com

pancha.ravi@gmail.com

ravi-panchal

github.com/ravipanchal88

(484) 456 6767

Philadelphia, PA

Work Experience

O Merck & Co

Project Manager/Scrum Master [May,2017 - Current]

- Orchestrated the solution discovery to migrate the data from IBM z/OS to Amazon Redshift.
- The Project will help Merck to save 3 million in 2018 and approximately 15 million until 2023.
- Managing two agile teams with different IT vendors to achieve project objective. The Project budget is 900K with 5 Developers (Onshore/Offshore).

O Almac Clinical Technologies

Project Manager/Scrum Master [Nov,2013 - Apr,2017]

- Led the company wide effort to improve the SDLC processes.
- Managed the Project to implement MS TFS within the company.
- Trained the software development team on new SDLC.
- Managed a Project to implement CA PPM and played active role in MDM & PPM COE.

O Merck & Co

Project Manager [May,2012 - Oct-2013]

- Managed multiple Data Archival projects simultaneously for the application that were being retired.
- Created a Project Dashboard in SharePoint with sql server backend.
- Orchestrated the validation of IBM Optim tool for use within Merck. This involved creating of SOP's, QASR, IQOQ documents.

O Children's Hospital of Philadelphia

Business Analyst/Project Manager [Nov,2011 - Apr,2012]

- Led the effort to gather requirements for new EEG and created an RFQ document for procurement.
- Managed a project for visitor security application.
- Initiated the discovery & preplanning for KRONOS workforce management tool.

O Barclaycard US

Business Analyst / Jr. Project Manager [Mar, 2008 - Oct, 2011]

- Orchestrated the effort to implement the Credit Card to Checking account ACH feature. The company had previously failed to get the feature launched twice.
- Played a pivotal role in TSYS SME for Customer Profitability Engine.
- Gathered requirement for Barclaycard US IVR system.

O Marsh & McLennan

Business Analyst / Test Analyst [Nov,2007 – Feb,2008]

- Gathered Requirements for IVR system.
- Tested the IVR Web Services.

O Harleysville Insurance

Jr. Business Analyst [Sep,2006 - Aug,2007]

Gathered Requirements for Harleysville claims system.

Skills

Project Management

Agile

Software Development Life Cycle(SDLC)

Business Analysis

Test Driven Development

Javascript

HTML

CSS

jQuery

AJAX JSON

Node JS

Express

ASP.NET

UNIX REACT

REDUX

Babel

ES6

Postgres

Heroku

AWS SOLServer

ADI

Education

- Bachelors in Computer Science
 D.Y.Patil College of Engg &
 Tech,INDIA
- Masters in Computer Science
 Newyork Institute of Technology, NY

Certification

- Certified Scrum Master(Scrum Alliance)
- Professional Scrum Master(Scrum.org)
- Full Stack Developer(NYCDA)

Volunteer & Causes

• Care By Giving Chief Technical Officer(CTO)